<theme>
  <variables>
    <systemName>Cave Story</systemName>
    <systemDescription>Cave Story, originally released as Dōkutsu Monogatari, is a 2004 Metroidvania platform-adventure game for Microsoft Windows. It was developed over five years by Japanese independent developer Daisuke "Pixel" Amaya in his free time. Cave Story features 2D platform mechanics and is reminiscent of the games Amaya played in his youth, such as Metroid and Castlevania. After its initial self-published release, the game slowly gained popularity on the internet. It received widespread critical acclaim for many polished aspects of its design, such as its compelling characters, setting, story, and gameplay. Cave Story is considered by many as the quintessential indie game because of its one-person development team and influence on the video gaming world. NXENGINE is a complete open-source clone/rewrite of the masterpiece jump-and-run platformer Doukutsu Monogatari (also known as Cave Story)</systemDescription>
    <systemManufacturer>Studio Pixel</systemManufacturer>
    <systemReleaseYear>2004</systemReleaseYear>
    <systemHardwareType>${i18n.hardware-engine}</systemHardwareType>
    <systemCoverSize>1-1</systemCoverSize>
    <systemCartSize>1-1</systemCartSize>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ar">
    <systemDescription>Cave Story، أصلاً صدرت باسم Dōkutsu Monogatari، هي لعبة منصات ومغامرة من نوع Metroidvania صدرت عام 2004 لنظام Microsoft Windows. طورها المطور الياباني المستقل Daisuke "Pixel" Amaya على مدار خمس سنوات خلال أوقات فراغه. تتميز Cave Story بعناصر منصات ثنائية الأبعاد وتستحضر طابع ألعاب مثل Metroid وCastlevania التي لعبها Amaya في شبابه. بعد نشرها الذاتي الأولي، اكتسبت اللعبة شعبية تدريجية على الإنترنت وحظيت بإشادة نقدية واسعة بسبب تصميمها المصقول وشخصياتها وجوها وقصتها وآليات اللعب. تعتبر Cave Story من قبل الكثيرين لعبة إيندي نموذجية بفضل كونها من تطوير شخص واحد وتأثيرها على عالم ألعاب الفيديو.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="bs">
    <systemDescription>Cave Story, izvorno objavljena kao Dōkutsu Monogatari, je Metroidvania platforma-avantura iz 2004. za Microsoft Windows. Razvio ju je pet godina japanski nezavisni developer Daisuke "Pixel" Amaya u svoje slobodno vrijeme. Cave Story sadrži 2D platformsku mehaniku i podsjeća na igre koje je Amaya igrao u mladosti, poput Metroida i Castlevania. Nakon početnog samostalnog izdanja, igra je polako stekla popularnost na internetu i dobila široko kritičko priznanje zbog mnogih dotjeranih aspekata dizajna, kao što su uvjerljivi likovi, ambijent, priča i gameplay. Mnogi smatraju Cave Story kultnim indie naslovom zbog razvoja jedne osobe i njenog utjecaja na svijet videoigara.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ca">
    <systemDescription>Cave Story, originalment publicada com Dōkutsu Monogatari, és un videojoc de plataformes i aventura del 2004 del tipus Metroidvania per a Microsoft Windows. Va ser desenvolupat durant cinc anys pel desenvolupador independent japonès Daisuke "Pixel" Amaya en el seu temps lliure. Cave Story presenta mecàniques de plataformes en 2D i recorda a jocs que Amaya va jugar durant la seva joventut, com Metroid i Castlevania. Després de la seva publicació inicial autoeditada, el joc va anar guanyant popularitat a Internet i va rebre àmplies crítiques favorables per diversos aspectes polits del seu disseny, com els seus personatges, ambient, història i jugabilitat. Molts consideren Cave Story com el joc indie per excel·lència a causa de l'equip de desenvolupament d'una sola persona i la seva influència en el món dels videojocs.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="de">
    <systemDescription>Cave Story, ursprünglich veröffentlicht als Dōkutsu Monogatari, ist ein 2004 erschienenes Metroidvania-Plattform-Adventure für Microsoft Windows. Es wurde über fünf Jahre hinweg vom japanischen Indie-Entwickler Daisuke "Pixel" Amaya in seiner Freizeit entwickelt. Cave Story bietet 2D-Plattform-Mechaniken und erinnert an Spiele, die Amaya in seiner Jugend spielte, wie Metroid und Castlevania. Nach der anfänglichen Selbstveröffentlichung gewann das Spiel im Internet langsam an Popularität und erhielt breite Anerkennung für viele ausgefeilte Aspekte seines Designs, wie seine fesselnden Charaktere, Schauplatz, Geschichte und Gameplay. Viele betrachten Cave Story als das Inbegriff-der-Indie-Spiele, aufgrund seines Einpersonen-Entwicklungsteams und seines Einflusses auf die Videospielwelt.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="es">
    <systemDescription>Cave Story, originalmente lanzado como Dōkutsu Monogatari, es un juego de plataformas y aventura tipo Metroidvania de 2004 para Microsoft Windows. Fue desarrollado durante cinco años por el desarrollador independiente japonés Daisuke "Pixel" Amaya en su tiempo libre. Cave Story presenta mecánicas de plataformas en 2D y recuerda a juegos que Amaya jugó en su juventud, como Metroid y Castlevania. Tras su lanzamiento autoeditado inicial, el juego fue ganando lentamente popularidad en Internet y recibió elogios de la crítica por sus aspectos de diseño pulidos, como sus personajes, ambientación, historia y jugabilidad. Muchos consideran Cave Story el arquetipo del juego indie debido a su equipo de desarrollo de una sola persona y su influencia en el mundo de los videojuegos.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="fr">
    <systemDescription>Cave Story, initialement publié sous le nom de Dōkutsu Monogatari, est un jeu de plateforme-aventure de type Metroidvania de 2004 pour Microsoft Windows. Il a été développé pendant cinq ans par le développeur indépendant japonais Daisuke "Pixel" Amaya pendant son temps libre. Cave Story propose une mécanique de plateforme en 2D et rappelle des jeux auxquels Amaya jouait dans sa jeunesse, tels que Metroid et Castlevania. Après sa publication auto-éditée initiale, le jeu a lentement gagné en popularité sur Internet et a reçu des éloges de la critique pour de nombreux aspects soignés de son design, comme ses personnages captivants, son univers, son histoire et son gameplay. Beaucoup considèrent Cave Story comme le jeu indépendant par excellence en raison de son équipe de développement composée d'une seule personne et de son influence sur le monde du jeu vidéo.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="hr">
    <systemDescription>Cave Story, izvorno objavljena kao Dōkutsu Monogatari, je Metroidvania platforma-avantura iz 2004. za Microsoft Windows. Razvio ju je pet godina japanski nezavisni programer Daisuke "Pixel" Amaya u svoje slobodno vrijeme. Cave Story sadrži 2D platformsku mehaniku i podsjeća na igre koje je Amaya igrao u mladosti, poput Metroida i Castlevanie. Nakon početnog samostalnog izdanja, igra je polako stekla popularnost na internetu i primila široko kritičko priznanje zbog mnogih dotjeranih aspekata dizajna, kao što su uvjerljivi likovi, ambijent, priča i gameplay. Mnogi smatraju Cave Story tipičnim indie naslovom zbog razvoja jedne osobe i njenog utjecaja na svijet videoigara.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="it">
    <systemDescription>Cave Story, originariamente pubblicato come Dōkutsu Monogatari, è un gioco platform-avventura in stile Metroidvania del 2004 per Microsoft Windows. È stato sviluppato per cinque anni dallo sviluppatore indipendente giapponese Daisuke "Pixel" Amaya nel suo tempo libero. Cave Story presenta meccaniche platform 2D e richiama giochi che Amaya giocava nella sua giovinezza, come Metroid e Castlevania. Dopo la sua pubblicazione auto-produttiva iniziale, il gioco ha lentamente guadagnato popolarità su Internet e ha ricevuto ampi elogi per molti aspetti rifiniti del suo design, come i suoi personaggi coinvolgenti, l'ambientazione, la storia e il gameplay. Molti considerano Cave Story il classico gioco indie per via del team di sviluppo di una sola persona e della sua influenza sul mondo dei videogiochi.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ja">
    <systemDescription>Cave Story（元々は Dōkutsu Monogatari として発表）は、2004年に Microsoft Windows 向けにリリースされた Metroidvania タイプのアクションアドベンチャーゲームです。日本のインディー開発者 Daisuke "Pixel" Amaya によって5年間の自由時間を使って制作されました。Cave Story は2Dプラットフォームの要素を持ち、Amaya が若い頃に遊んだ Metroid や Castlevania といったゲームを彷彿とさせます。自主制作での初期公開後、インターネット上で徐々に人気を博し、魅力的なキャラクター、世界観、ストーリー、ゲームプレイなど、デザインの多くの洗練された側面が高く評価されました。Cave Story は、1人で開発されたという点とビデオゲーム界への影響から、多くの人にとって典型的なインディーゲームと見なされています。</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ko">
    <systemDescription>Cave Story는 원래 Dōkutsu Monogatari로 출시된 2004년작 Metroidvania형 플랫폼 어드벤처 게임으로 Microsoft Windows용으로 발매되었습니다. 일본의 인디 개발자 Daisuke "Pixel" Amaya가 여가 시간에 5년에 걸쳐 개발했습니다. Cave Story는 2D 플랫폼 메커니즘을 특징으로 하며 Amaya가 젊었을 때 즐겼던 Metroid와 Castlevania와 유사한 점이 있습니다. 초기 자체 배포 이후, 이 게임은 인터넷에서 점차 인기를 얻었고 매력적인 캐릭터, 설정, 스토리 및 게임플레이 등 디자인의 여러 다듬어진 측면으로 비평가들의 광범위한 찬사를 받았습니다. 많은 사람들은 한 사람의 개발팀과 비디오 게임 세계에 대한 영향 때문에 Cave Story를 전형적인 인디 게임으로 간주합니다.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="nl">
    <systemDescription>Cave Story, oorspronkelijk uitgebracht als Dōkutsu Monogatari, is een Metroidvania platform-avonturenspel uit 2004 voor Microsoft Windows. Het werd gedurende vijf jaar ontwikkeld door de Japanse onafhankelijke ontwikkelaar Daisuke "Pixel" Amaya in zijn vrije tijd. Cave Story bevat 2D-platformmechanieken en doet denken aan de spellen die Amaya in zijn jeugd speelde, zoals Metroid en Castlevania. Na de aanvankelijke zelfuitgave kreeg het spel langzaam populairiteit op internet en het kreeg brede lof van critici voor vele gepolijste aspecten van het ontwerp, zoals de overtuigende personages, setting, verhaal en gameplay. Veel mensen beschouwen Cave Story als het ultieme indie-spel vanwege het eenpersoonsontwikkelteam en de invloed op de videogamewereld.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="pl">
    <systemDescription>Cave Story, pierwotnie wydana jako Dōkutsu Monogatari, to gra platformowo-przygodowa w stylu Metroidvania z 2004 roku na Microsoft Windows. Była rozwijana przez pięć lat przez japońskiego niezależnego twórcę Daisuke "Pixel" Amaya w jego wolnym czasie. Cave Story zawiera mechaniki platformowe 2D i przypomina gry, w które Amaya grał w młodości, takie jak Metroid i Castlevania. Po początkowym samodzielnym wydaniu gra powoli zdobywała popularność w internecie i zyskała szerokie uznanie krytyków za wiele dopracowanych aspektów projektu, takich jak przekonujące postacie, otoczenie, fabuła i rozgrywka. Wielu uważa Cave Story za wzorcową grę indie ze względu na jednolity zespół deweloperski i wpływ na świat gier wideo.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="pt">
    <systemDescription>Cave Story, originalmente lançado como Dōkutsu Monogatari, é um jogo de plataformas-aventura Metroidvania de 2004 para Microsoft Windows. Foi desenvolvido ao longo de cinco anos pelo desenvolvedor independente japonês Daisuke "Pixel" Amaya no seu tempo livre. Cave Story apresenta mecânicas de plataformas 2D e lembra jogos que Amaya jogou na sua juventude, como Metroid e Castlevania. Após o seu lançamento auto-publicado inicial, o jogo foi ganhando lentamente popularidade na internet e recebeu amplo reconhecimento crítico por muitos aspectos polidos do seu design, como personagens cativantes, ambientação, história e jogabilidade. Muitos consideram Cave Story o exemplo clássico de jogo indie devido à sua equipa de desenvolvimento constituída por uma só pessoa e à sua influência no mundo dos videojogos.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ro">
    <systemDescription>Cave Story, inițial lansat ca Dōkutsu Monogatari, este un joc de platformă-aventură de tip Metroidvania din 2004 pentru Microsoft Windows. A fost dezvoltat timp de cinci ani de către dezvoltatorul independent japonez Daisuke "Pixel" Amaya în timpul liber. Cave Story are mecanici de platformă 2D și amintește de jocurile pe care Amaya le juca în tinerețe, precum Metroid și Castlevania. După lansarea sa inițială autpublicată, jocul a câștigat treptat popularitate pe internet și a primit aprecieri critice larg răspândite pentru multe aspecte bine finisate ale designului său, precum personaje convingătoare, decor, poveste și gameplay. Mulți consideră Cave Story drept exemplul clasic de joc indie din cauza echipei de dezvoltare formată dintr-o singură persoană și a influenței sale asupra lumii jocurilor video.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ru">
    <systemDescription>Cave Story, первоначально выпущенная как Dōkutsu Monogatari, — это платформер-приключение в жанре Metroidvania 2004 года для Microsoft Windows. Она была разработана в течение пяти лет японским инди-разработчиком Дайсуке «Pixel» Амайя в его свободное время. Cave Story использует 2D-платформенные механики и напоминает игры, в которые Амайя играл в молодости, такие как Metroid и Castlevania. После первоначального самостоятельного релиза игра постепенно набирала популярность в интернете и получила широкое признание критиков за многие отточенные аспекты дизайна, такие как убедительные персонажи, атмосфера, сюжет и игровой процесс. Многие считают Cave Story квинтэссенцией инди-игр из-за одночленной команды разработки и её влияния на мир видеоигр.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="sr">
    <systemDescription>Cave Story, оригинално објављена као Dōkutsu Monogatari, је Metroidvania platforma-avantura из 2004. за Microsoft Windows. Развио ју је пет година јапански независни програмер Daisuke "Pixel" Amaya у своје слободно време. Cave Story садржи 2D платформске механике и подсећа на игре које је Amaya играо у младости, попут Metroid-а и Castlevania-е. Након почетног самопубликованог издања, игра је полако стекла популарност на интернету и добила широку критичку похвалу за многе уређене аспекте свог дизајна, попут уверљивих ликова, атмосфере, приче и игре. Многи сматрају да је Cave Story оличење инди-игра због тима за развој од једне особе и утицаја на свет видео игара.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="sv">
    <systemDescription>Cave Story, ursprungligen utgiven som Dōkutsu Monogatari, är ett Metroidvania-plattformsspel från 2004 för Microsoft Windows. Det utvecklades under fem år av den japanska indieutvecklaren Daisuke "Pixel" Amaya på hans fritid. Cave Story har 2D-plattformsmekanik och påminner om spel Amaya spelade i sin ungdom, såsom Metroid och Castlevania. Efter sin initiala självpublicerade utgivning blev spelet långsamt populärt på internet och fick bred kritikermottagning för många förfinade aspekter av dess design, som dess fängslande karaktärer, miljö, berättelse och spelmekanik. Många betraktar Cave Story som det typiska indie-spelet på grund av dess enpersoners utvecklingsteam och påverkan på spelvärlden.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="zh">
    <systemDescription>Cave Story，最初以 Dōkutsu Monogatari 的名义发布，是一款 2004 年面向 Microsoft Windows 的 Metroidvania 平台冒险游戏。它由日本独立开发者 Daisuke "Pixel" Amaya 在他的业余时间历时五年开发完成。Cave Story 具有 2D 平台机制，让人联想到 Amaya 年轻时玩的游戏，如 Metroid 和 Castlevania。在最初的自发布之后，这款游戏在互联网上逐渐走红，并因其精心打磨的设计方面（如引人入胜的角色、设定、剧情和游戏性）而获得广泛好评。由于其单人开发团队以及对电子游戏界的影响，许多人认为 Cave Story 是典型的独立游戏代表。</systemDescription>
  </variables>
</theme>
