<theme>
  <variables>
    <systemName>Philips CD-i</systemName>
    <systemManufacturer>Philips</systemManufacturer>
    <systemReleaseYear>1991</systemReleaseYear>
    <systemDescription>The Philips CD-i (Compact Disc Interactive) is an interactive multimedia CD player developed and marketed by Royal Philips Electronics N.V. This category of device was created to provide more functionality than an audio CD player or game console, but at a lower price than a personal computer with CD-ROM drive at the time. The cost savings were due to the lack of a hard drive, floppy drive, keyboard, mouse, monitor (a standard television was used), and less operating system software. In addition to games, educational and multimedia reference titles were produced, such as interactive encyclopedias, museum tours, etc. before public Internet access was widespread. Competitors included the Tandy VIS and Commodore CDTV. Seen as a game console, the CD-i format proved to be a commercial failure. The company lost nearly one billion dollars on the entire project. The failure of the CD-i caused Philips to leave the video game industry after it was discontinued. The CD-i is also one of the earliest consoles to implement internet features, including subscriptions, web browsing, downloading, e-mail, and online play. This was facilitated by the use of an additional hardware modem that Philips released in 1996.</systemDescription>
    <systemDescription lang="es">El Philips CD-i (Compact Disc Interactive) es un reproductor de CD multimedia interactivo desarrollado y comercializado por Royal Philips Electronics N.V. Esta categoría de dispositivo se creó para ofrecer más funcionalidad que un reproductor de CD de audio o una consola de videojuegos, pero a un precio inferior al de una computadora personal con unidad de CD-ROM de la época. El ahorro se debió a la ausencia de disco duro, disquetera, teclado, ratón, monitor (se utilizaba un televisor estándar) y a la menor cantidad de software de sistema operativo. Además de juegos, se produjeron títulos de referencia educativos y multimedia, como enciclopedias interactivas, visitas a museos, etc., antes de que se generalizara el acceso público a Internet. Entre sus competidores se encontraban Tandy VIS y Commodore CDTV. Considerado una consola de videojuegos, el formato CD-i resultó ser un fracaso comercial. La compañía perdió casi mil millones de dólares en todo el proyecto. El fracaso del CD-i provocó que Philips abandonara la industria de los videojuegos tras su descontinuación. El CD-i es también una de las primeras consolas en implementar funciones de Internet, como suscripciones, navegación web, descargas, correo electrónico y juegos en línea. Esto se facilitó gracias al uso de un módem de hardware adicional que Philips lanzó en 1996.</systemDescription>
    <systemHardwareType>Console</systemHardwareType>
    <systemHardwareType lang="es">Consola</systemHardwareType>
    <systemCoverSize>1-1</systemCoverSize>
    <systemCartSize>1-1</systemCartSize>
  </variables>
</theme>