<theme>
  <variables>
    <systemName>AdvanceMAME</systemName>
    <systemDescription>AdvanceMAME, is a port of the MAME 0.106 and MESS 0.106 emulators for Arcade Monitors and TVs but also for LCDs and PC monitors.</systemDescription>
    <systemManufacturer>MAME</systemManufacturer>
    <systemReleaseYear>1998</systemReleaseYear>
    <systemHardwareType>${i18n.hardware-emulator}</systemHardwareType>
    <systemCoverSize>3-4</systemCoverSize>
    <systemCartSize>1-1</systemCartSize>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ar">
    <systemDescription>AdvanceMAME، هو منفذ لمحاكيات MAME 0.106 و MESS 0.106 لمحاكيات شاشات الأركيد وأجهزة التلفاز وكذلك لشاشات LCD وشاشات الكمبيوتر الشخصي.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="bs">
    <systemDescription>AdvanceMame, luka je mame 0.106 i nered 0,106 emulatora za arkadne monitore i televizore, ali i za LCDS i PC monitore.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ca">
    <systemDescription>AdvanceMame, és un port de la MAME 0.106 i embolica 0.106 emuladors per a monitors i televisors d’arcades, però també per a monitors LCDs i PC.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="de">
    <systemDescription>AdvanceMAME, ist eine Portierung der MAME 0.106 und MESS 0.106 Emulatoren für Arcade Monitore und TVs aber auch für LCDs und PC Monitore.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="es">
    <systemDescription>AdvanceMAME, es un port de los emuladores MAME 0.106 y MESS 0.106 para Monitores Arcade y TVs pero también para LCDs y monitores de PC.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="fr">
    <systemDescription>AdvanceMAME est un portage des émulateurs MAME 0.106 et MESS 0.106 pour les moniteurs d'arcade et les téléviseurs, mais aussi pour les écrans LCD et les moniteurs PC.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="hr">
    <systemDescription>AdvanceMame, luka je MAME 0,106 i nered 0,106 emulatora za arkadne monitore i TV -ove, ali i za LCD -ove i PC monitore.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="it">
    <systemDescription>AdvanceMAME è un porting degli emulatori MAME 0.106 e MESS 0.106 per monitor e TV Arcade ma anche per LCD e monitor PC.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ja">
    <systemDescription>AdvanceMAMEは、MAME 0.106とMESS 0.106のエミュレーターをアーケードモニターとテレビ、LCDとPCモニター用に移植したものです。</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ko">
    <systemDescription>AdvanceMAME는 아케이드 모니터 및 TV용 MAME 0.106 및 MESS 0.106 에뮬레이터뿐만 아니라 LCD 및 PC 모니터용 에뮬레이터의 포트입니다.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="nl">
    <systemDescription>AdvanceMAME, is een port van de MAME 0.106 en MESS 0.106 emulators voor Arcade Monitoren en TV's maar ook voor LCD's en PC monitoren.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="pl">
    <systemDescription>AdvanceMAME, to port emulatorów MAME 0.106 i MESS 0.106 dla monitorów Arcade i telewizorów, ale także dla LCD i monitorów PC.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="pt">
    <systemDescription>O AdvanceMAME é uma porta dos emuladores MAME 0.106 e MESS 0.106 para monitores e TVs de fliperama, mas também para LCDs e monitores de PC.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ro">
    <systemDescription>AdvanceMAME, este un port al emulatoarelor MAME 0.106 și MESS 0.106 pentru monitoare Arcade și televizoare, dar și pentru LCD-uri și monitoare PC.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ru">
    <systemDescription>AdvanceMAME - это порт эмуляторов MAME 0.106 и MESS 0.106 для аркадных мониторов и телевизоров, а также для LCD и PC мониторов.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="sr">
    <systemDescription>АДАНЦЕМАМЕМЕ, је лука маме 0,106 и неред 0.106 емулатора за аркадне мониторе и телевизора, али и за ЛЦДС и ПЦ мониторе.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="sv">
    <systemDescription>AdvanceMAME, är en portning av emulatorerna MAME 0.106 och MESS 0.106 för arkadmonitorer och TV-apparater men även för LCD- och PC-monitorer.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="zh">
    <systemDescription>AdvanceMAME是MAME 0.106和MESS 0.106模拟器的移植版，适用于街机显示器和电视，也适用于液晶显示器和电脑显示器。</systemDescription>
  </variables>
</theme>
