<theme>
  <variables>
    <systemName>Mega Man</systemName>
    <systemManufacturer>Capcom</systemManufacturer>
    <systemReleaseYear>Various</systemReleaseYear>
    <systemReleaseYear lang="es">Varios</systemReleaseYear>

    <systemDescription>Mega Man (known as Rockman[a] in Japan) is a video game franchise developed and published by Capcom, featuring the protagonist of the same name. The original game was released for the Nintendo Entertainment System in 1987, and spawned a franchise that expanded to over 50 games on multiple systems. As of March 2025, the series had sold 43 million units worldwide.[1] Mega Man has been popular among gamers and has been reimagined and evolved as a video game character for over 30 years.

The main series, dubbed the "Classic" series, consists of eleven games, the standalone Mega Man & Bass, the spin-off Game Boy series (released in Japan as Rockman World), and various ports, remakes, and compilations. The storyline of the "Classic" series is succeeded by the Mega Man X, Mega Man Zero, Mega Man ZX, and the Mega Man Legends series, all of which set in a single continuity. Two other series, the Mega Man Battle Network and Mega Man Star Force series, take place in an alternate universe where the internet flourished rather than robotics.</systemDescription>
    <systemDescription lang="es">Mega Man, conocido en Japón como Rockman (ロックマン Rokkuman?), es una franquicia de videojuegos creada por Capcom, que tiene como protagonista a Mega Man o a sus contrapartes. Es uno de los personajes más reconocidos de los videojuegos, creado por Akira Kitamura en 1987 para el Nintendo Entertainment System. Aunque originalmente se propusieron los nombres de Mighty Kid, Knuckle Kid, y Rainbow Battle Kid por su capacidad de cambiar de color al momento de absorber los poderes de sus enemigos, Capcom finalmente se decidió por "Rockman" como el apodo japonés de Mega Man. Hasta marzo de 2025 la franquicia ha vendido 43 000 000 copias.</systemDescription>
    <systemHardwareType>Custom Collection</systemHardwareType>
    <systemHardwareType lang="es">Colección Personalizada</systemHardwareType>
    <systemCoverSize>1-1</systemCoverSize>
    <systemCartSize>1-1</systemCartSize>
  </variables>
</theme>
