<theme>
  <variables>
    <systemName>Sega Model 1</systemName>
    <systemDescription>The Sega Model 1 is an arcade system board that was released by Sega in 1992 and is the successor to the Sega System 32 (released in 1990). While earlier Sega hardware was capable of handling 3D polygons (such as the Mega Drive, released in 1988), the Model 1 was Sega's first hardware specifically designed for 3D polygon graphics.</systemDescription>
    <systemManufacturer>Sega</systemManufacturer>
    <systemReleaseYear>1992</systemReleaseYear>
    <systemHardwareType>${i18n.hardware-arcade}</systemHardwareType>
    <systemCoverSize>3-4</systemCoverSize>
    <systemCartSize>1-1</systemCartSize>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ar">
    <systemDescription>لوحة ألعاب الأركيد Sega Model 1 صدرت من Sega في عام 1992 وهي الخلف لـ Sega System 32 (1990). بينما كانت أجهزة Sega السابقة قادرة على التعامل مع مضلعات ثلاثية الأبعاد، كان Model 1 أول جهاز مصمم خصيصاً لرسوميات المضلعات ثلاثية الأبعاد.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="bs">
    <systemDescription>Sega Model 1 je arcade ploča koju je Sega izdala 1992. i nasljednik je Sega System 32 (1990). Dok su raniji Sega hardveri bili sposobni za rad s 3D poligonima, Model 1 je bio prvi hardver tvrtke posebno dizajniran za 3D poligonsku grafiku.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ca">
    <systemDescription>La placa d'arcade Sega Model 1 va ser llançada per Sega el 1992 i és la successora de la Sega System 32 (1990). Mentre l'hardware anterior de Sega podia manejar polígons 3D, el Model 1 va ser el primer maquinari de Sega dissenyat específicament per a gràfics de polígons 3D.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="de">
    <systemDescription>Das Sega Model 1 ist eine Arcade-Systemplatine, die Sega 1992 herausbrachte und der Nachfolger des Sega System 32 (1990) ist. Während frühere Sega-Hardware bereits 3D-Polygone verarbeiten konnte, war das Model 1 Segas erste Hardware, die speziell für 3D-Polygon-Grafik ausgelegt war.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="es">
    <systemDescription>La placa arcade Sega Model 1 fue lanzada por Sega en 1992 y es la sucesora de la Sega System 32 (1990). Mientras que el hardware anterior de Sega podía manejar polígonos 3D, el Model 1 fue el primer hardware de Sega específicamente diseñado para gráficos de polígonos 3D.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="fr">
    <systemDescription>La carte arcade Sega Model 1 est sortie chez Sega en 1992 et succède à la Sega System 32 (1990). Alors que le matériel Sega précédent était capable de gérer des polygones 3D, le Model 1 fut le premier matériel de Sega spécifiquement conçu pour les graphiques polygonaux 3D.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="hr">
    <systemDescription>Sega Model 1 je arkadna ploča koju je Sega izdala 1992. i nasljednik je Sega System 32 (1990). Dok je raniji Sega hardver mogao prikazivati 3D poligone, Model 1 je bio prvi hardver tvrtke posebno dizajniran za 3D poligonsku grafiku.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="it">
    <systemDescription>La scheda arcade Sega Model 1 è stata rilasciata da Sega nel 1992 ed è la successore della Sega System 32 (1990). Mentre l'hardware Sega precedente era in grado di gestire poligoni 3D, il Model 1 è stato il primo hardware di Sega progettato specificamente per la grafica a poligoni 3D.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ja">
    <systemDescription>Sega Model 1 は 1992 年に Sega がリリースしたアーケード基板で、Sega System 32（1990 年）の後継機です。以前の Sega ハードウェアが 3D ポリゴンを扱うことができた一方で、Model 1 は 3D ポリゴングラフィックス専用に設計された Sega 初のハードウェアでした。</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ko">
    <systemDescription>Sega Model 1은 1992년 Sega에서 출시한 아케이드 시스템 보드로, Sega System 32(1990)의 후속 모델입니다. 이전의 Sega 하드웨어도 3D 폴리곤을 처리할 수 있었지만, Model 1은 3D 폴리곤 그래픽을 위해 특별히 설계된 Sega의 첫 하드웨어였습니다。</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="nl">
    <systemDescription>De Sega Model 1 is een arcade-systeemkaart die in 1992 door Sega werd uitgebracht en de opvolger is van de Sega System 32 (1990). Terwijl eerdere Sega-hardware 3D-polygons kon verwerken, was de Model 1 Segas eerste hardware die specifiek voor 3D-polygonengrafiek was ontworpen.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="pl">
    <systemDescription>Sega Model 1 to arkadowa płyta systemowa wydana przez Segę w 1992 roku, będąca następcą Sega System 32 (1990). Podczas gdy wcześniejszy sprzęt Segi potrafił obsługiwać trójwymiarowe wielokąty, Model 1 był pierwszym sprzętem Segi zaprojektowanym specjalnie do grafiki 3D opartej na poligonach.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="pt">
    <systemDescription>A Sega Model 1 é uma placa de sistema arcade lançada pela Sega em 1992 e é a sucessora da Sega System 32 (1990). Enquanto o hardware anterior da Sega era capaz de lidar com polígonos 3D, o Model 1 foi o primeiro hardware da Sega especificamente projetado para gráficos de polígonos 3D.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ro">
    <systemDescription>Sega Model 1 este o board arcade lansat de Sega în 1992 și este succesorul Sega System 32 (1990). În timp ce hardware-ul Sega anterior putea gestiona poligoane 3D, Model 1 a fost primul hardware Sega proiectat special pentru grafica cu poligoane 3D.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ru">
    <systemDescription>Sega Model 1 — аркадная системная плата, выпущенная Sega в 1992 году, ставшая преемницей Sega System 32 (1990). В то время как более раннее оборудование Sega могло работать с 3D-полигонами, Model 1 был первым оборудованием Sega, специально разработанным для отображения 3D-полигональной графики.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="sr">
    <systemDescription>Sega Model 1 је аркадна плоча коју је Sega објавила 1992. године и наследник је Sega System 32 (1990). Док је ранији Sega хардвер могао руковати 3D полигонима, Model 1 је био први хардвер компаније посебно дизајниран за 3D полигонску графику.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="sv">
    <systemDescription>Sega Model 1 är ett arkadsystemkort som släpptes av Sega 1992 och är efterföljaren till Sega System 32 (1990). Medan tidigare Sega-hårdvara kunde hantera 3D-polygona, var Model 1 Segas första hårdvara som specifikt utformats för 3D-polygongrafik.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="zh">
    <systemDescription>Sega Model 1 是世嘉在 1992 年推出的街机系统主板，是 Sega System 32（1990 年）的继任者。虽然早期的世嘉硬件已能处理 3D 多边形，但 Model 1 是世嘉首款专门为 3D 多边形图形设计的硬件。</systemDescription>
  </variables>
</theme>
