<theme>
  <variables>
    <systemName>Sega Model 2</systemName>
    <systemManufacturer>Sega</systemManufacturer>
    <systemReleaseYear>1993</systemReleaseYear>
    <systemDescription>The Sega Model 2 is an arcade system board originally debuted by Sega in 1993 as a successor to the Sega Model 1 board. It is an extension of the Model 1 hardware, most notably introducing the concept of texture-mapped polygons, allowing for more realistic 3D graphics (for its time). The Model 2 board was an important milestone for the arcade industry, and helped launch several key arcade franchises of the 90s, including Daytona USA, Virtua Cop, Sega Rally Championship, Dead or Alive, Virtua Striker, Cyber Troopers Virtual-On and The House of the Dead. The Model 2 was engineered with help from GE Aerospace (acquired by Martin Marietta in 1993, now part of Lockheed Martin), who designed the texture-mapping technology incorporated by the Model 2. The Model 2's development was led by famed game designer Yu Suzuki. The Model 2 arcade board debuted along with Daytona USA, a game which was finished, copyrighted and debuted at the JAMMA arcade show in 1993. There four versions of the system: the original Model 2 and the Model 2A-CRX, Model 2B-CRX and Model 2C-CRX variants. Model 2 and 2A-CRX used a custom DSP with internal code for the geometrizer while 2B-CRX and 2C-CRX used well documented DSPs and uploaded the geometrizer code at startup to the DSP.</systemDescription>
    <systemDescription lang="es">La Sega Model 2 es una placa base para arcade que Sega lanzó originalmente en 1993 como sucesora de la Sega Model 1. Es una extensión del hardware de la Model 1, que introdujo notablemente el concepto de polígonos con texturas mapeadas, lo que permitió gráficos 3D más realistas (para su época). La Model 2 marcó un hito importante en la industria de las recreativas y contribuyó al lanzamiento de varias franquicias clave de los años 90, como Daytona USA, Virtua Cop, Sega Rally Championship, Dead or Alive, Virtua Striker, Cyber ​​Troopers Virtual-On y The House of the Dead. La Model 2 fue diseñada con la ayuda de GE Aerospace (adquirida por Martin Marietta en 1993, ahora parte de Lockheed Martin), quien diseñó la tecnología de texturas mapeada que incorpora la Model 2. El desarrollo de la Model 2 estuvo a cargo del afamado diseñador de juegos Yu Suzuki. La placa arcade Modelo 2 debutó junto con Daytona USA, un juego terminado, registrado y presentado en la feria de arcade JAMMA de 1993. Existían cuatro versiones del sistema: el Modelo 2 original y las variantes Modelo 2A-CRX, Modelo 2B-CRX y Modelo 2C-CRX. Los Modelos 2 y 2A-CRX utilizaban un DSP personalizado con código interno para el geometrizador, mientras que los Modelos 2B-CRX y 2C-CRX utilizaban DSP bien documentados y cargaban el código del geometrizador al iniciarse.</systemDescription>
    <systemHardwareType>Arcade</systemHardwareType>
    <systemCoverSize>3-4</systemCoverSize>
    <systemCartSize>1-1</systemCartSize>
  </variables>
</theme>