<theme>
  <variables>
    <systemName>Namco System 246/256</systemName>
    <systemDescription>The Namco System 246/256 is an arcade platform based on the Sony PlayStation 2. Sometimes referred to as Namco 2x6, as the two hardwares are very similar and run much of the same software. The system is comprised of a motherboard and optical or hard disk drive, housed in a large metal case. Software is booted from a security dongle and runs either straight off supplied optical media (DVD-ROM or CD-ROM), or a hard drive.The security dongle is cosmetically and electrically identical to a PS2 memory card, but contains different security algorithms to prevent unauthorized copying. There are no regional restrictions inherent to any dongle, media, or chassis, but many games were released with limited export regulations in the form of licensing or legal text at boot.</systemDescription>
    <systemManufacturer>Namco/Sony</systemManufacturer>
    <systemReleaseYear>2001</systemReleaseYear>
    <systemHardwareType>${i18n.hardware-arcade}</systemHardwareType>
    <systemCoverSize>3-4</systemCoverSize>
    <systemCartSize>1-1</systemCartSize>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ar">
    <systemDescription>نظام الألعاب الأركيد Namco System 246/256 مبني على منصة Sony PlayStation 2. يُشار إليه أحيانًا باسم Namco 2x6 لأن الهاردويرين متشابهان جدًا ويشغلان الكثير من نفس البرامج. يتألف النظام من لوحة أم ومحرك أقراص بصري أو صلب داخل حاوية معدنية كبيرة. يتم تشغيل البرمجيات من دونجل أمني وتعمل إما مباشرة من وسط بصري مزود (DVD-ROM أو CD-ROM) أو من قرص صلب. الدونجل الأمني مماثل شكليًا وكهربائيًا لبطاقة ذاكرة PS2 لكنه يحتوي على خوارزميات أمان مختلفة لمنع النسخ غير المصرح به.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="bs">
    <systemDescription>Namco System 246/256 je arkadna platforma bazirana na Sony PlayStation 2. Ponekad se naziva Namco 2x6, jer su oba hardvera vrlo slična i pokreću mnogo istog softvera. Sistem se sastoji od matične ploče i optičkog ili tvrdog diska, smještenih u velikom metalnom kućištu. Softver se učitava s sigurnosnog dongla i radi ili direktno sa priloženog optičkog medija (DVD-ROM ili CD-ROM), ili sa tvrdog diska. Sigurnosni dongle je vizuelno i električno identičan PS2 memorijskoj kartici, ali sadrži različite sigurnosne algoritme kako bi se spriječilo neovlašteno kopiranje.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ca">
    <systemDescription>El Namco System 246/256 és una plataforma d'arcade basada en la Sony PlayStation 2. De vegades es refereix com Namco 2x6, ja que els dos maquinari són molt similars i executen gran part del mateix programari. El sistema està compost per una placa base i una unitat òptica o disc dur, allotjades en una gran caixa metàl·lica. El programari s'inicia des d'un dongle de seguretat i s'executa directament des del suport òptic subministrat (DVD-ROM o CD-ROM) o des d'un disc dur. El dongle de seguretat és estètica i elèctricament idèntic a una targeta de memòria de PS2, però conté algorismes de seguretat diferents per evitar la còpia no autoritzada.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="de">
    <systemDescription>Das Namco System 246/256 ist eine Arcade-Plattform, die auf der Sony PlayStation 2 basiert. Manchmal als Namco 2x6 bezeichnet, da die beiden Hardwareversionen sehr ähnlich sind und viele der gleichen Softwaretitel ausführen. Das System besteht aus einem Motherboard und einem optischen Laufwerk oder einer Festplatte, untergebracht in einem großen Metallgehäuse. Software wird von einem Sicherheitsdongle gebootet und läuft entweder direkt von mitgeliefertem optischem Medium (DVD-ROM oder CD-ROM) oder von einer Festplatte. Der Sicherheitsdongle ist kosmetisch und elektrisch identisch mit einer PS2-Speicherkarte, enthält jedoch andere Sicherheitsalgorithmen, um unerlaubtes Kopieren zu verhindern.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="es">
    <systemDescription>El Namco System 246/256 es una plataforma arcade basada en la Sony PlayStation 2. A veces se conoce como Namco 2x6, ya que ambos hardware son muy similares y ejecutan gran parte del mismo software. El sistema está compuesto por una placa base y una unidad óptica o disco duro, alojados en una gran carcasa metálica. El software se inicia desde un dongle de seguridad y se ejecuta ya sea directamente desde el medio óptico suministrado (DVD-ROM o CD-ROM), o desde un disco duro. El dongle de seguridad es cosméticamente y eléctricamente idéntico a una tarjeta de memoria de PS2, pero contiene algoritmos de seguridad diferentes para evitar la copia no autorizada.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="fr">
    <systemDescription>Le Namco System 246/256 est une plateforme d'arcade basée sur la Sony PlayStation 2. Parfois appelé Namco 2x6, car les deux matériels sont très similaires et exécutent une grande partie des mêmes logiciels. Le système se compose d'une carte mère et d'un lecteur optique ou d'un disque dur, logés dans un grand boîtier métallique. Les logiciels sont démarrés à partir d'un dongle de sécurité et s'exécutent soit directement à partir du média optique fourni (DVD-ROM ou CD-ROM), soit à partir d'un disque dur. Le dongle de sécurité est esthétiquement et électriquement identique à une carte mémoire PS2, mais contient des algorithmes de sécurité différents pour empêcher la copie non autorisée.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="hr">
    <systemDescription>Namco System 246/256 je arkadna platforma temeljena na Sony PlayStation 2. Ponekad se naziva Namco 2x6, jer su oba hardvera vrlo slična i pokreću veliki dio iste softverske biblioteke. Sustav se sastoji od matične ploče i optičkog ili tvrdog diska, smještenih u velikom metalnom kućištu. Softver se pokreće s sigurnosnog dongla i radi ili izravno s priloženog optičkog medija (DVD-ROM ili CD-ROM), ili s tvrdog diska. Sigurnosni dongle je kozmetički i električno identičan PS2 memorijskoj kartici, ali sadrži različite sigurnosne algoritme kako bi se spriječilo neovlašteno kopiranje.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="it">
    <systemDescription>Il Namco System 246/256 è una piattaforma arcade basata sulla Sony PlayStation 2. A volte indicata come Namco 2x6, poiché i due hardware sono molto simili ed eseguono gran parte dello stesso software. Il sistema è composto da una scheda madre e da un'unità ottica o disco rigido, alloggiati in un grande chassis metallico. Il software viene avviato da un dongle di sicurezza e viene eseguito direttamente dal supporto ottico fornito (DVD-ROM o CD-ROM) o da un disco rigido. Il dongle di sicurezza è esteriormente ed elettricamente identico a una memory card PS2, ma contiene algoritmi di sicurezza diversi per impedire la copia non autorizzata.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ja">
    <systemDescription>Namco System 246/256 は Sony PlayStation 2 をベースにしたアーケードプラットフォームです。両方のハードウェアは非常に似ており、同じソフトウェアの多くを実行するため、Namco 2x6 と呼ばれることもあります。システムはマザーボードと光学ドライブまたはハードディスクドライブで構成され、大型の金属ケースに収納されています。ソフトウェアはセキュリティドングルからブートされ、提供された光学メディア（DVD-ROM または CD-ROM）から直接、またはハードドライブから実行されます。セキュリティドングルは外観や電気的には PS2 メモリーカードと同一ですが、無断コピーを防ぐために異なるセキュリティアルゴリズムが組み込まれています。</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ko">
    <systemDescription>Namco System 246/256는 Sony PlayStation 2를 기반으로 하는 아케이드 플랫폼입니다. 두 하드웨어가 매우 유사하여 Namco 2x6로 불리기도 합니다. 시스템은 대형 금속 케이스에 수납된 마더보드와 광학 또는 하드 디스크 드라이브로 구성됩니다. 소프트웨어는 보안 도글에서 부팅되며 제공된 광매체(DVD-ROM 또는 CD-ROM)에서 직접 실행되거나 하드 드라이브에서 실행됩니다. 보안 도글은 외형 및 전기적으로 PS2 메모리 카드와 동일하지만 무단 복제를 방지하기 위해 다른 보안 알고리즘을 포함합니다.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="nl">
    <systemDescription>Het Namco System 246/256 is een arcadeplatform gebaseerd op de Sony PlayStation 2. Soms aangeduid als Namco 2x6, omdat de twee hardwareversies zeer op elkaar lijken en veel van dezelfde software draaien. Het systeem bestaat uit een moederbord en een optische of harde schijf, ondergebracht in een grote metalen behuizing. Software wordt gestart vanaf een beveiligingsdongle en draait of rechtstreeks vanaf het geleverde optische medium (DVD-ROM of CD-ROM) of vanaf een harde schijf. De beveiligingsdongle is cosmetisch en elektrisch identiek aan een PS2-geheugenkaart, maar bevat andere beveiligingsalgoritmen om ongeoorloofd kopiëren te voorkomen.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="pl">
    <systemDescription>Namco System 246/256 to platforma arcade oparta na Sony PlayStation 2. Czasami określana jako Namco 2x6, ponieważ oba sprzęty są bardzo podobne i uruchamiają wiele tego samego oprogramowania. System składa się z płyty głównej oraz napędu optycznego lub dysku twardego, umieszczonych w dużej metalowej obudowie. Oprogramowanie jest uruchamiane z klucza zabezpieczającego i działa albo bezpośrednio z dostarczonego nośnika optycznego (DVD-ROM lub CD-ROM), albo z dysku twardego. Klucz zabezpieczający jest zewnętrznie i elektrycznie identyczny z kartą pamięci PS2, ale zawiera inne algorytmy zabezpieczające, aby uniemożliwić nieautoryzowane kopiowanie.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="pt">
    <systemDescription>O Namco System 246/256 é uma plataforma arcade baseada na Sony PlayStation 2. Às vezes referido como Namco 2x6, pois os dois hardwares são muito semelhantes e executam grande parte do mesmo software. O sistema é composto por uma placa-mãe e uma unidade óptica ou disco rígido, alojados numa grande caixa metálica. O software é inicializado a partir de um dongle de segurança e é executado quer diretamente a partir do suporte ótico fornecido (DVD-ROM ou CD-ROM), quer a partir de um disco rígido. O dongle de segurança é cosmeticamente e eletricamente idêntico a um cartão de memória PS2, mas contém algoritmos de segurança diferentes para evitar cópia não autorizada.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ro">
    <systemDescription>Namco System 246/256 este o platformă arcade bazată pe Sony PlayStation 2. Uneori este denumit Namco 2x6, deoarece cele două hardware-uri sunt foarte similare și rulează o mare parte din același software. Sistemul este alcătuit dintr-o placă de bază și o unitate optică sau hard disk, găzduite într-o carcasă metalică mare. Software-ul pornește de pe un dongle de securitate și rulează fie direct de pe mediul optic furnizat (DVD-ROM sau CD-ROM), fie de pe un hard disk. Dongle-ul de securitate este cosmetic și electric identic cu un card de memorie PS2, dar conține algoritmi de securitate diferiți pentru a preveni copierea neautorizată.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ru">
    <systemDescription>Namco System 246/256 — это аркадная платформа, основанная на Sony PlayStation 2. Иногда её называют Namco 2x6, поскольку оба варианта аппаратного обеспечения очень похожи и запускают большую часть одного и того же программного обеспечения. Система состоит из материнской платы и оптического или жёсткого диска, размещённых в большом металлическом корпусе. Программное обеспечение загружается с защитного донгла и выполняется либо прямо с поставляемого оптического носителя (DVD-ROM или CD-ROM), либо с жёсткого диска. Защитный донгл внешне и электрически идентичен карте памяти PS2, но содержит другие алгоритмы безопасности для предотвращения несанкционированного копирования.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="sr">
    <systemDescription>Namco System 246/256 је аркадна платформа заснована на Sony PlayStation 2. Понекад се назива Namco 2x6, јер су два хардвера веома слична и покрећу већи део истог софтвера. Систем се састоји од матичне плоче и оптичког или тврдог диска, смештених у великом металном кућишту. Софтвер се покреће са сигурносног донгла и ради или директно са испорученог оптичког медија (DVD-ROM или CD-ROM), или са тврдог диска. Сигурносни донгл је козметички и електрично идентичан PS2 меморијској картици, али садржи различите сигурносне алгоритме како би се спречило неовлашћено копирање.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="sv">
    <systemDescription>Namco System 246/256 är en arkadplattform baserad på Sony PlayStation 2. Ibland kallad Namco 2x6, eftersom de två hårdvaruversionerna är mycket lika och kör mycket av samma mjukvara. Systemet består av ett moderkort och en optisk enhet eller hårddisk, inrymt i ett stort metallchassi. Mjukvara startas från en säkerhetsdongel och körs antingen direkt från det medföljande optiska mediet (DVD-ROM eller CD-ROM), eller från en hårddisk. Säkerhetsdongeln är kosmetiskt och elektriskt identisk med ett PS2-minneskort, men innehåller andra säkerhetsalgoritmer för att förhindra obehörig kopiering.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="zh">
    <systemDescription>Namco System 246/256 是基于 Sony PlayStation 2 的街机平台。有时称为 Namco 2x6，因为这两种硬件非常相似并运行许多相同的软件。该系统由主板和光驱或硬盘组成，安装在大型金属外壳中。软件由安全加密狗引导，运行方式要么直接从提供的光学介质（DVD-ROM 或 CD-ROM），要么从硬盘。安全加密狗在外观和电气上与 PS2 存储卡相同，但包含不同的安全算法以防止未经授权的复制。</systemDescription>
  </variables>
</theme>
