<theme>
  <variables>
    <systemName>Pokémon Mini</systemName>
    <systemManufacturer>Nintendo</systemManufacturer>
    <systemReleaseYear>2001</systemReleaseYear>
    <systemDescription>The Pokémon Mini is a handheld game console that was designed and manufactured by Nintendo and themed around the Pokémon media franchise. It is the smallest game system with interchangeable cartridges ever produced by Nintendo, weighing just under two and a half ounces (70 grams). It was first released in North America on November 16, 2001, then in Japan on December 14, 2001, and in Europe on March 15, 2002. The systems were released in three colors: Wooper Blue, Chikorita Green, and Smoochum Purple. Features of the Pokémon mini include an internal real-time clock, an infrared port used to facilitate multiplayer gaming, a reed switch for detecting shakes, and a motor used to implement force feedback. The GameCube game Pokémon Channel features playable demo versions of several Pokémon mini games via console emulation. Also included in the game is Snorlax's Lunch Time, a Pokémon Channel exclusive. Some games were only released in Japan, such as Togepi's Adventure.</systemDescription>
    <systemDescription lang="es">Pokémon Mini es una consola portátil diseñada y fabricada por Nintendo con la temática de la franquicia Pokémon. Es la consola con cartuchos intercambiables más pequeña jamás producida por Nintendo, con un peso de poco menos de 70 gramos. Se lanzó por primera vez en Norteamérica el 16 de noviembre de 2001, luego en Japón el 14 de diciembre de 2001 y en Europa el 15 de marzo de 2002. Las consolas se lanzaron en tres colores: Azul Wooper, Verde Chikorita y Morado Smoochum. Las características de Pokémon Mini incluyen un reloj interno en tiempo real, un puerto infrarrojo para facilitar el juego multijugador, un interruptor de lengüeta para detectar vibraciones y un motor para implementar la retroalimentación de fuerza. El juego Pokémon Channel de GameCube presenta versiones demo jugables de varios minijuegos de Pokémon mediante emulación de consola. También se incluye en el juego Snorlax's Lunch Time, una exclusiva de Pokémon Channel. Algunos juegos solo se lanzaron en Japón, como Togepi's Adventure.</systemDescription>
    <systemHardwareType>Portable</systemHardwareType>
    <systemHardwareType lang="es">Portátil</systemHardwareType>
    <systemCoverSize>1-1</systemCoverSize>
    <systemCartSize>1-1</systemCartSize>
  </variables>
</theme>