<theme>
  <variables>
    <systemName>Satellaview</systemName>
    <systemManufacturer>Nintendo</systemManufacturer>
    <systemReleaseYear>1995</systemReleaseYear>
    <systemDescription>The Satellaview is a satellite modem peripheral for Nintendo's Super Famicom system that was released in Japan in 1995. Available for pre-release orders beginning February 13, 1995, the Satellaview retailed for between ¥14,000 and 18,000 (at the time between USD$141 and 182) and came bundled with the BS-X Game Pak and an 8M Memory Pak. The Satellaview system was developed and released by Nintendo to receive signals broadcast from satellite TV station WOWOW's satellite radio subsidiary, St.GIGA. St.GIGA was responsible for file server management, maintenance, and vocalization for "SoundLink" games. Nintendo data broadcasts were given a fixed time slot known as the Super Famicom Hour during which scrambled Satellaview-related data was streamed via radio waves to be unscrambled by St.GIGA's "BS digital hi-vision TV." As a subscription-based station for ambient and New Age music, St.GIGA listeners were already equipped with "BS tuners" prior to St.GIGA's contract with Nintendo. Satellaview owners who lacked a "BS tuner" had to purchase one separately from St.GIGA at a price of ¥33,000, as well as sign up for Nintendo's and St.GIGA's monthly joint membership fees. Alternatively, users could rent "BS tuners" from St.GIGA for a 6-month period at a price of ¥5,400. Even at this premium price, St.GIGA reported subscriptions peaking at 116,378 households by March 1997, and dropping to around 46,000 by June 2001.</systemDescription>
    <systemDescription lang="es">Satellaview es un periférico de módem satelital para la consola Super Famicom de Nintendo, lanzado en Japón en 1995. Disponible para pedidos anticipados a partir del 13 de febrero de 1995, su precio oscilaba entre ¥14,000 y ¥18,000 (en aquel entonces, entre USD$141 y USD$182) e incluía el cartucho de juego BS-X y un cartucho de memoria de 8 MB. Nintendo desarrolló y lanzó Satellaview para recibir señales emitidas por St.GIGA, la filial de radio satelital de la cadena de televisión por satélite WOWOW. St.GIGA se encargaba de la gestión, el mantenimiento y la vocalización de los servidores de archivos para los juegos "SoundLink". Las transmisiones de datos de Nintendo tenían una franja horaria fija, conocida como la Hora Super Famicom, durante la cual los datos codificados de Satellaview se transmitían por ondas de radio para ser decodificados por la "BS Digital Hi-Vision TV" de St.GIGA. Como emisora ​​de música ambiental y new age por suscripción, los oyentes de St.GIGA ya contaban con sintonizadores BS antes del contrato de St.GIGA con Nintendo. Los propietarios de Satellaview que no contaban con un sintonizador BS debían adquirir uno por separado de St.GIGA por 33.000 yenes, además de suscribirse a las cuotas mensuales conjuntas de Nintendo y St.GIGA. Como alternativa, los usuarios podían alquilar sintonizadores BS de St.GIGA durante seis meses por 5.400 yenes. Incluso con este precio elevado, St.GIGA informó que las suscripciones alcanzaron un máximo de 116.378 hogares en marzo de 1997 y descendieron a unos 46.000 en junio de 2001.</systemDescription>
    <systemHardwareType>Peripheral</systemHardwareType>
    <systemHardwareType lang="es">Periférico</systemHardwareType>
    <systemCoverSize>3-4</systemCoverSize>
    <systemCartSize>1-1</systemCartSize>
  </variables>
</theme>